<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Krustlet – </title>
    <link>https://docs.krustlet.dev/en/topics/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Krustlet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://docs.krustlet.dev/en/topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>En: </title>
      <link>https://docs.krustlet.dev/en/topics/architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.krustlet.dev/en/topics/architecture/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h1 id=&#34;krustlet-architecture&#34;&gt;Krustlet architecture&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This document describes the Krustlet architecture at a high level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-purpose-of-krustlet&#34;&gt;The purpose of Krustlet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Krustlet acts as a Kubernetes Kubelet by listening on the Kubernetes API&amp;rsquo;s event
stream for new Pod requests that match a particular set of node selectors,
scheduling those workloads to run using a WASI-based runtime instead of a
container-based runtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;implementation&#34;&gt;Implementation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Krustlet is written in Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By acting as a Kubelet, Krustlet uses Kubernetes client libraries to communicate
with the Kubernetes API. Currently, the client libraries use HTTP(s) as the
communication protocol between Krustlet and the Kubernetes API, using JSON as
the data format for serializing and de-serializing request bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Krustlet sends status updates about scheduled pods to the Kubernetes API.
Therefore, it does not require its own database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;providers&#34;&gt;Providers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Krustlet uses &lt;a href=&#34;./providers.md&#34;&gt;providers&lt;/a&gt; to interact with a given runtime. The
&lt;code&gt;kubelet&lt;/code&gt; crate has the common functionality for listing to a stream of pods (an
&amp;ldquo;Informer&amp;rdquo; in Kubernetes parlance), keeping a node status updated, and handling
requests from the Kubernetes API. The Kubelet expects to be given a provider
(something that implements the &lt;code&gt;Provider&lt;/code&gt; interface) which knows how to create
&amp;ldquo;containers&amp;rdquo; for the runtime it is implementing. Note that these might not
actually be Docker containers (they definitely are not if you are using one of
the providers implemented in this repository), but Kubernetes still thinks of
them as a &amp;ldquo;container.&amp;rdquo; The basic workflow is like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;kubelet&lt;/code&gt; receives a pod event from the stream&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depending on the event type (added, modified, deleted), it calls the
corresponding &lt;code&gt;Provider&lt;/code&gt; method and creates, updates, or stops/deletes the
&amp;ldquo;container&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;Provider&lt;/code&gt; does work and returns an error if there is a problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>En: </title>
      <link>https://docs.krustlet.dev/en/topics/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.krustlet.dev/en/topics/configuration/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h1 id=&#34;configuration&#34;&gt;Configuration&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;kubelet&lt;/code&gt; crate supports configuration via the command line, configuration
file or environment variables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; Custom kubelets built using the &lt;code&gt;kubelet&lt;/code&gt; crate can choose which of
these methods to support, or may choose to bypass &lt;code&gt;kubelet&lt;/code&gt;&amp;rsquo;s built-in
configuration system in favour of their own. &lt;code&gt;krustlet-wasi&lt;/code&gt; uses standard
configuration and supports all configuration methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; Certain flags must be handled at the provider or custom kubelet level.
If you are building a custom kubelet using the &lt;code&gt;kubelet&lt;/code&gt; crate, please see the
&amp;ldquo;Notes to kubelet implementers&amp;rdquo; section below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;configuration-values&#34;&gt;Configuration values&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Command line&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Environment variable&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Configuration file&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-a, &amp;ndash;addr&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;KRUSTLET_ADDRESS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;listenerAddress&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The address on which the kubelet should listen&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;ndash;data-dir&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;KRUSTLET_DATA_DIR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;dataDir&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The path under which the kubelet should store data (e.g. logs, container images, etc.). The default is &lt;code&gt;$HOME/.krustlet&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;ndash;hostname&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;KRUSTLET_HOSTNAME&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;hostname&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The name of the host where the kubelet runs. Defaults to the hostname of the machine where the kubelet is running; pass this if the name in the TLS certificate does not match the actual machine name&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;ndash;max-pods&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;MAX_PODS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;maxPods&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The maximum number of pods to schedule on the kubelet at any one time. The default is 110&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-n, &amp;ndash;node-ip&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;KRUSTLET_NODE_IP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;nodeIP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The IP address of the node registered with the Kubernetes master. Defaults to the IP address of the kubelet hostname, as obtained from DNS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;ndash;node-labels&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NODE_LABELS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;nodeLabels&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The labels to apply to the node when it registers in the cluster. See below for format&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;ndash;node-name&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;KRUSTLET_NODE_NAME&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;nodeName&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The name by which to refer to the kubelet node in Kubernetes. Defaults to the hostname&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-p, &amp;ndash;port&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;KRUSTLET_PORT&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;listenerPort&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The port on which the kubelet should listen. The default is 3000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;ndash;cert-file&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;KRUSTLET_CERT_FILE&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;tlsCertificateFile&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The path to the TLS certificate for the kubelet. The default is &lt;code&gt;(data directory)/config/krustlet.crt&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;ndash;private-key-file&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;KRUSTLET_PRIVATE_KEY_FILE&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;tlsPrivateKeyFile&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The path to the private key for the TLS certificate. The default is &lt;code&gt;(data directory)/config/krustlet.key&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;ndash;insecure-registries&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;KRUSTLET_INSECURE_REGISTRIES&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;insecureRegistries&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A list of registries that should be accessed using HTTP instead of HTTPS. On the command line or environment variable, use commas to separate multiple registries&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;ndash;x-allow-local-modules&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;KRUSTLET_ALLOW_LOCAL_MODULES&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;allowLocalModules&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;If true, the kubelet should recognise references prefixed with &amp;lsquo;fs&amp;rsquo; as indicating a filesystem path rather than a registry location. This is an experimental flag for use in development scenarios where you don&amp;rsquo;t want to repeatedly push your local builds to a registry; it is likely to be removed in a future version when we have a more comprehensive toolchain for local development.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;node-labels-format&#34;&gt;Node labels format&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you specify node labels on the command line or in an environment variable,
the format is a comma-separated list of &lt;code&gt;name=value&lt;/code&gt; pairs. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34; data-lang=&#34;text&#34;&gt;--node-labels mylabel=foo,myotherlabel=bar
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you specify node labels in the configuration file, the format is key-value
pairs. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-json&#34; data-lang=&#34;json&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;node_labels&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;mylabel&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#4e9a06&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;foo&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;myotherlabel&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#4e9a06&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;bar&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;configuration-file-location&#34;&gt;Configuration file location&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default, the configuration file is located at
&lt;code&gt;$HOME/.krustlet/config/config.json&lt;/code&gt;. The &lt;code&gt;kubelet&lt;/code&gt; crate does not define a
common way to override this.  However, custom kubelets built on &lt;code&gt;kubelet&lt;/code&gt; may
provide such a mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;krustlet-wasi&lt;/code&gt; kubelet does not currently provide a way to override the
default location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TODO: should we build in a standard way of overriding the file location?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;precedence&#34;&gt;Precedence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you specify the same setting in multiple places - for example, both in the
configuration file and on the command line - then the precedence is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Command line flags take precedence over environment variables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Environment variables take precedence over the configuration file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This allows you to conveniently override individual settings from a
configuration file, for example by writing &lt;code&gt;MAX_PODS=200 krustlet-wasi&lt;/code&gt; or
&lt;code&gt;krustlet-wasi --max-pods 200&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you specify node labels in multiple places, the collections are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;
combined: the place with the highest precedence takes effect and all others are
ignored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes-to-kubelet-implementers&#34;&gt;Notes to kubelet implementers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some flags require you to support them in your provider or main code - they are
not implemented automatically by the kubelet core. These flags are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;--bootstrap-file&lt;/code&gt; - should be passed to &lt;code&gt;kubelet::bootstrap&lt;/code&gt; if you use the
bootstrapping feature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;--data-dir&lt;/code&gt; - this should be used to construct the &lt;code&gt;FileStore&lt;/code&gt; if you use one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;--x-allow-local-modules&lt;/code&gt; - if specified you should compose a
&lt;code&gt;FileSystemStore&lt;/code&gt; onto your normal store&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;code&gt;krustlet-wasi.rs&lt;/code&gt; file for examples of how to honour these flags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can&amp;rsquo;t honour a flag value in your particular scenario, then you should
still check for it and return an error, rather than silently ignoring it.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>En: </title>
      <link>https://docs.krustlet.dev/en/topics/csi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.krustlet.dev/en/topics/csi/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h1 id=&#34;the-container-storage-interface&#34;&gt;The Container Storage Interface&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Container Storage Interface (CSI) is a standardized plugin system that
enables many different types of storage systems to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatically provision storage volumes as needed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mount volumes to pods as needed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unmount volumes from deleted or removed pods, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Destroy storage volumes after they&amp;rsquo;ve been de-commissioned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Krustlet introduced this feature in v0.6.0 and is currently in alpha status.
Many features that Kubernetes supports such as &amp;ldquo;Block&amp;rdquo; mounting or read-only
access modes are currently unavailable, but will become available as the feature
stabilizes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-csi&#34;&gt;Why CSI?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without CSI support, adding a new storage system to a Provider requires checking
code into the core Krustlet repository, and it requires each Provider to call
this code in order to support the new volume type. Any changes to the storage
system won&amp;rsquo;t become available until the next Krustlet release, and could be
painful for many Providers to adopt these new changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CSI addresses these issues by enabling storage plugins to be developed
out-of-tree, deployed alongside a Krustlet Provider, and consumed through
standard Kubernetes storage primitives: PersistentVolumeClaims (PVC),
PersistentVolumes (PV), and StorageClasses (SC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-i-deploy-a-csi-driver-alongside-a-krustlet-provider&#34;&gt;How do I deploy a CSI driver alongside a Krustlet Provider?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please see the &lt;a href=&#34;../howto/csi.md&#34;&gt;HOWTO guide&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-i-use-a-csi-volume&#34;&gt;How do I use a CSI Volume?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please see the &lt;a href=&#34;../howto/csi.md&#34;&gt;HOWTO guide&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;where-can-i-find-csi-drivers&#34;&gt;Where can I find CSI Drivers?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CSI drivers are maintained and distributed by the community. You can find
example CSI drivers in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kubernetes-csi&#34;&gt;kubernetes-csi&lt;/a&gt;
organization on GitHub. These are provided purely for illustrative purposes, and
are not intended for use in production.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>En: </title>
      <link>https://docs.krustlet.dev/en/topics/glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.krustlet.dev/en/topics/glossary/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h1 id=&#34;glossary&#34;&gt;Glossary&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is where you will find definitions for commmon terminology used across
Krustlet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;kubelet&#34;&gt;Kubelet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kubelet is a key piece of the Kubernetes architecture. A kubelet is a &amp;ldquo;node
agent&amp;rdquo; that runs on each node in a Kubernetes cluster. It registers as a node
with the Kubernetes API, waiting for new &lt;a href=&#34;#pod&#34;&gt;pods&lt;/a&gt; provided by the API, and
ensures the workloads in those pods are running and healthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pod&#34;&gt;Pod&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A pod is the simplest execution unit in Kubernetes that you can create and
destroy using the Kubernetes API. Nearly every workload type available in
Kubernetes (Deployments, StatfulSets, DaemonSets, Jobs, etc.) uses pods as the
basic unit of work. In other words, a pod represents a single unit of work in
your cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;provider&#34;&gt;Provider&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A provider is an abstract interface within Krustlet. Providers describe the
verbs and actions a WebAssembly runtime (like wasmtime) must provide in order
for that runtime to work as a kubelet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary responsibility of a provider is to execute a workload (or schedule
it on an external executor), monitor that workload, and expose important details
back to Kubernetes using the Kubelet API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See also the topic guide on &lt;a href=&#34;providers.md&#34;&gt;providers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>En: </title>
      <link>https://docs.krustlet.dev/en/topics/plugin_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.krustlet.dev/en/topics/plugin_system/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h1 id=&#34;plugin-system-overview&#34;&gt;Plugin System Overview&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Krustlet partially implements the plugin discovery system used by the mainline
Kubelet for purposes of supporting CSI. The CSI documentation points at the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/extend-kubernetes/compute-storage-net/device-plugins/#device-plugin-registration&#34;&gt;device plugin documentation&lt;/a&gt;,
but upon further investigation/reverse engineering, we determined that CSI
plugins use the auto plugin discovery method implemented
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kubernetes/kubernetes/tree/fd74333a971e2048b5fb2b692a9e043483d63fba/pkg/kubelet/pluginmanager&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
You can also see other evidence of this in the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kubernetes-csi/drivers/blob/master/pkg/csi-common/nodeserver-default.go&#34;&gt;csi-common code&lt;/a&gt;
and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kubernetes-csi/node-driver-registrar/blob/be7678e75e23b5419624ae3983b66957c0991073/README.md&#34;&gt;Node Driver Registrar
documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-not-supported&#34;&gt;What is not supported?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently we do not support the &lt;code&gt;DevicePlugin&lt;/code&gt; type or the aforementioned newer
device plugin system. Currently we do not have plans to implement it, but that
could change in the future as needs/uses evolve&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-does-it-work&#34;&gt;How does it work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plugin registration system has an event driven loop for discovering and
registering plugins:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kubelet using a file system watcher to watch the given directory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plugins wishing to register themselves with Kubelet must open a Unix domain
socket (henceforth referred to as just &amp;ldquo;socket&amp;rdquo;) in the watched directory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When Kubelet detects a new socket, it connects to the discovered socket and
attempts to do a &lt;code&gt;GetInfo&lt;/code&gt; gRPC call.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the info returned from the &lt;code&gt;GetInfo&lt;/code&gt; call, Kubelet performs validation
to make sure it supports the correct version of the API requested by the
plugin and that the plugin is not already registered. If it is a &lt;code&gt;CSIPlugin&lt;/code&gt;
type, the info will also contain another path to a socket where the CSI
driver is listening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If validation succeeds, Kubelet makes a &lt;code&gt;NotifyRegistrationStatus&lt;/code&gt; gRPC call
on the originally discovered socket to inform the plugin that it has
successfully registered&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;additional-information&#34;&gt;Additional information&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In normal Kubernetes land, most CSI plugins register themselves with the Kubelet
using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kubernetes-csi/node-driver-registrar&#34;&gt;Node Driver
Registrar&lt;/a&gt; sidecar
container that runs with the actual CSI driver. It has the responsibilty for
creating the socket that Kubelet discovers.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>En: </title>
      <link>https://docs.krustlet.dev/en/topics/providers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.krustlet.dev/en/topics/providers/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h1 id=&#34;providers&#34;&gt;Providers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default runtime for the Krustlet project is &lt;code&gt;wasi&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;wasi&lt;/code&gt; runtime uses a project called
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bytecodealliance/wasmtime&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;wasmtime&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. wasmtime is a
standalone JIT-style host runtime for WebAssembly modules. It is focused
primarily on standards compliance with the WASM specification as it relates to
&lt;a href=&#34;https://wasi.dev/&#34;&gt;WASI&lt;/a&gt;. If your WebAssembly module complies with the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/WebAssembly/spec&#34;&gt;WebAssembly specification&lt;/a&gt;, wasmtime can
run it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important to note that the WASI standard and &lt;code&gt;wasmtime&lt;/code&gt; are still under
heavy development. There are some key features (like networking) that are
currently missing, but will be made available in future updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;additional-providers&#34;&gt;Additional Providers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are various other providers available as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wasmCloud/krustlet-wasmcloud-provider&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;wasmcloud&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: The
&lt;code&gt;wasmcloud&lt;/code&gt; runtime is a secure WebAssembly host runtime, connecting &amp;ldquo;actors&amp;rdquo;
and &amp;ldquo;capability providers&amp;rdquo; together to connect your WebAssembly runtime to
cloud-native services like message brokers, databases, or other external
services normally unavailable to the WebAssembly runtime. This provider used
to be available in this repo but was moved under the wasmCloud project so it
could be maintained both by the Krustlet maintainers and the wasmCloud
maintainers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kflansburg/krustlet-cri&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;CRI&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: A Container Runtime
Interface provider implementation for Krustlet. This runtime allows you to run
the containers you know and love within Krustlet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
